hotjar.com 2016-04-28

# Hotjar – Privacy Policy

Date: 1st April 2015  
Version number: 2.0 

* * *

At Hotjar your privacy matters to us and we are committed to respect and protect your privacy and your personal information.

This Privacy Policy forms part of our Terms of Use and describes our privacy practices.

Our Privacy Policy explains the details of how Hotjar collects information from your browser and device when you access website pages. We also explain the choices we offer, making sure you are in control of your personal information at all times.

By visiting our website or by visiting one of our client's websites (which will provide you with notice of its use of Hotjar and this policy) or by signing up via our website, you acknowledge that you accept and consent to our privacy practices as outlined in this policy.

### Who and what is Hotjar?

Hotjar is a new all-in-one Analysis and Feedback tool that reveals the online behaviour and feedback of a website's visitors. By combining both A) Analysis and B) Feedback tools, Hotjar gives our clients the 'big picture' of how to improve their site's experience and its performance.

The Analysis tools allow you to measure and observe user behaviour (what users do) while the Feedback tools allow you to hear what your users say (Voice of User / Customer).

### How does Hotjar work?

By evaluating and analyzing feedback and behavioural patterns across a website's pages, through our code, software and service, our clients can improve the functionality of their websites and make them more user-friendly, more valuable and simpler for you to use.

Although this might sound scary, we ensure you that by sharing your behavioural patterns and any other information as described in this policy, with us and with our clients, you would be helping our clients provide you with a better experience and service.

Hotjar is run by Hotjar Ltd, a European startup incorporated in and headquartered in Malta. You can reach out with any questions or feedback by contacting us here.

### What information we collect:

We collect information in the following ways:

  * **Active collection:** information you provide to us when signing up to Hotjar. When creating a Hotjar account or signing-up for content or offers, we may ask you to provide us with your name, email address and details about your organization. We will only use this information to provide you with the service that you signed-up for and where we would like to use the contact details you have provided us with for any other purpose we will inform you and obtain your consent before proceeding. For info on how to deactivate your account and/or unsubscribe from receiving content or offers, kindly contact us here.

  * **Passive collection:** information which is automatically collected, without your knowledge, whilst navigating through and interacting with the content on our site and the content on each of our clients' site pages, as well as information on your device or computer (such as cookies).

The sole purpose of passively collecting your information is to improve your experience when using our clients' sites and web services.

Through the Hotjar tracking code embedded by our client on their website, the information collected includes:

    * **Device-specific data**

The following information may be collected through your device and browser:

      * your device's IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format);
      * device screen size;
      * device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information;
      * geographic location (country only);
      * preferred language used to display the webpage.
    * **Log data**

Our servers automatically record information which is created upon using Hotjar. Data includes:

      * referring domain;
      * pages visited;
      * geographic location (country only);
      * preferred language used to display the webpage;
      * date and time when website pages were accessed;
    * **Cookies**

Our website (www.hotjar.com) uses cookies to collect non-personal information including standard internet log information and details of your behavioural patterns upon visiting our website pages. We do this to provide you with a better experience, identify preferences, diagnose technical problems, analyse trends and to improve our website.

Cookies are small data files transferred onto computers or devices by websites for record-keeping purposes and to enhance functionality on the website.

We may also use cookies to record login details on your device or computer. This helps to determine whether a particular device previously visited our website so that the login details would not have to be re-entered each time you visit our website.

Most browsers allow you to choose whether to accept cookies or not. If you do not wish to have cookies placed on your computer, please set your browser preferences to reject all cookies, before accessing Hotjar or other websites owned by our clients that may use Hotjar. Please note that by doing so some features of the website you visit may be unavailable.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

For more info about the cookies we use, visit Cookie Information.

    * **Third Party Services**

Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By using Hotjar, you consent to the processing of data by these third parties in accordance with their privacy policies.

### How Hotjar collects information

We provide our clients with a tracking code, which will be used to collect your information and transmit this to our servers based in Ireland. When you visit a website which makes use of Hotjar, this tracking code will automatically collect the information based on your activity and store it in our servers, for our client's analysis. Information will also be collected from cookies which will be placed on your computer or device by the website.

We do not knowingly or intentionally collect any personal information from minors.

### Access to and Disclosure of information on Hotjar

The information collected can only be accessible by users designated on the client's Hotjar account. It may also be accessible by Hotjar and Amazon Web Services in certain limited circumstances. Other than explained in this section, we do not rent, sell or disclose your personal information to third parties, for their own use. 

  * We will not disclose any information to any third party. It may be necessary to share your personal information or part of it, with Amazon Web Services which store the information within their servers, solely related to the storage facilities. Amazon is bound by confidentiality.
  * We will also disclose your personal information as well as any client information where we are bound to do so, at law or via a court order, to meet any legal or regulatory requirement or obligations. We will use all reasonable efforts to ensure that those requirements or obligations are in accordance with applicable law.
  * We reserve the right to disclose your information as well as client information to any third party if we have reasonable information to believe that the disclosure is necessary for the purpose of an investigation and for the enforcement of any breaches of the terms and conditions of use, to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, protect the rights and interests as well as the property of Hotjar.
  * Any disclosures for other purposes, including disclosures with any other third parties not mentioned in this policy, shall require your consent. The disclosure of any sensitive personal information shall require your consent.
  * We may also share aggregated non-personal information with the public or with any third party for advertising the Hotjar service.

### How we secure Hotjar data

We have implemented various measures to ensure that the information is adequately protected against unauthorised access, use, disclosure and destruction. Please keep in mind that risk can never be eliminated but can be significantly reduced. All measures which we have taken significantly reduce the risk. We will not be held liable by any third party in the event of unauthorized access, use and/or disclosure of information.

Measures include:

  * Access to the information stored within our servers is restricted to a limited number of Hotjar employees and to users designated on our client's accounts. Amazon Web Services can access the information only in specific and limited circumstances. Our employees, our clients and these third parties are bound by confidentiality.
  * Our servers are protected by a) firewalls establishing a barrier between our trusted, secure internal network and the internet and b) IP restrictions, limiting access to whitelisted IPs.
  * Each client may only access information pertaining to the sites it is tracking and to the users browsing on its website pages.
  * We use HTTPS for our site pages and services providing secure transfer of data to prevent wiretapping and man-in-the-middle attacks.
  * We will review our information collection and processing practices periodically and we will review and amend this privacy policy accordingly.

### Choice

You may opt-out from having Hotjar collect your information when visiting a Hotjar website at any time by using a ‘Do Not Track’ header. You can read more on how to do that by clicking here.

You may deactivate your Hotjar account and / or unsubscribe from receiving content or offers from us at any time, by contacting us here.

### Changes to this Policy

We may revise this policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy, found at www.hotjar.com/privacy will govern our use of your information. We will notify you of any material changes to this policy via email to the email associated to your account. By continuing to access or use Hotjar, after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised privacy policy.

### Further Information

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us here.
